<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CropWise</string>
    <string name="first_name">First Name</string>
    <string name="last_name">Last Name</string>
    <string name="email">Email</string>
    <string name="password">Password</string>
    <string name="signup">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="user_name">User Name</string>
    <string name="log_in">Log In</string>
    <string name="this_is_profile_page">This is profile page</string>
    <string name="nitrogen">Nitrogen</string>
    <string name="phosphorus">Phosphorus</string>
    <string name="pottasium">Pottasium</string>
    <string name="crop_recommendation">Crop Recommendation:</string>
    <string name="mothbeans">MothBeans</string>
    <string name="mothbeansdesc">Moth beans are superstars of adaptability. They thrive in dry, well-drained sandy soil, but can tolerate a wide range of soil types including clay. They don\'t need much specific fertilizer, but a balanced NPK fertilizer can give them a boost. As for climate, moth beans love hot weather and can even handle some salinity. Watering is minimal - they\'re known for being drought-resistant.</string>
    <string name="coffee">Coffee</string>
    <string name="coffeedesc">Coffee trees are particular about their roots. They prefer well-draining, fertile soil with good aeration. Ideally, this would be a deep, sandy loam or a volcanic red earth rich in organic matter. Coffee thrives in a warm and humid climate with consistent temperatures around 23-28°C. When it comes to nutrients, coffee needs a balanced NPK fertilizer, but the specific ratio can vary depending on the soil and bean type. And while they love moisture, coffee plants don\'t tolerate soggy roots. Regular watering is key, but avoid overdoing it.</string>
    <string name="rice">Rice</string>
    <string name="ricedesc">Rice is a water lover! Clay or clay loam soils with excellent water retention are its favorite. This semi-aquatic plant needs significant nitrogen (N) for foliage, as well as a moderate amount of phosphorus (P) and potassium (K).  Rice flourishes in warm, humid climates with lots of rainfall. Since rice requires standing water for significant periods of its growth, frequent and controlled flooding of the fields is necessary.</string>
    <string name="chickpeas">ChickPeas</string>
    <string name="chickpeadesc">Chickpeas are surprisingly versatile when it comes to soil. They perform best in well-drained loams with good air circulation, but can tolerate sandier soils as long as drainage is excellent.  While chickpeas don\'t require a ton of fertilizer, a balanced NPK blend can boost yields. They prefer cool, dry climates with mild winters and don\'t tolerate excessive moisture. Watering needs are moderate, with deep irrigations during flowering and pod development being most crucial.</string>
    <string name="cotton">Cotton</string>
    <string name="cottondesc">Cotton thrives in sunny, warm climates with moderate rainfall. Ideally, the soil is well-drained and deep, allowing its roots to explore. Sandy loams or clay loams with a slightly acidic to slightly alkaline pH (6.0-8.0) are perfect. Nutrient-wise, cotton is a fan of balanced NPK fertilizer, needing more nitrogen early on for vigorous growth and then favoring phosphorus and potassium for boll development. While it can withstand dry periods, consistent watering throughout the growing season is crucial for optimal yields.</string>
    <string name="maizedesc">Maize loves deep, fertile, and well-drained soils – think of rich loams. They are hungry feeders, requiring ample nitrogen (N), phosphorus (P), and potassium (K) for optimal growth. Maize thrives in warm climates with ample sunshine and consistent summer rainfall. Adequate watering, especially during tasseling and grain-filling stages, is crucial. However, be careful not to overwater, as they don\'t tolerate waterlogging.</string>
    <string name="maize">Maize/Corn</string>
    <string name="coconutdesc">Coconuts are surprisingly adaptable! They flourish in well-drained sandy loams all the way to rich alluvial soils. Even coastal or reclaimed land can work. They tolerate a wide range of pH and some salinity. While not super picky eaters, a balanced NPK fertilizer helps them thrive. They love the tropics – hot and humid with consistent rainfall (1300-2300mm annually). Watering needs are moderate, but consistent. Don\'t let them dry out completely, especially during fruit development.</string>
    <string name="coconut">Coconut</string>
    <string name="blackgramdesc">Black gram is a superstar of adaptability! It tolerates a wide range of soils, from well-drained sandy loams to heavier clay soils, as long as drainage is good. They don\'t demand a lot of fertilizer, but a balanced NPK blend with a bit more phosphorus (P) can boost yields. Warm, humid climates with moderate rainfall suit them best. While they can handle dry periods, consistent moisture during flowering and pod filling is key for optimal production.</string>
    <string name="blackgram">BlackGram</string>
    <string name="jute">Jute</string>
    <string name="jutedesc">Jute thrives in warm, humid climates with ample monsoon rains. Rich, well-drained alluvial soils along rivers are ideal for its long, deep roots. While Jute benefits from a balanced NPK fertilizer, it needs less nitrogen (N) compared to other crops.  During its fast-growing stage, consistent moisture is essential, but jute doesn\'t tolerate waterlogging. Careful monitoring and drainage are key for a successful harvest.</string>
    <string name="kidneybeansdesc">Kidney beans are flexible when it comes to soil, tolerating sandy to clay as long as drainage is excellent. Loamy soil is ideal. They don\'t require heavy fertilization, but a balanced NPK fertilizer can give them a nudge. Warm weather with plenty of sun is their happy place. Watering is key, especially during flowering and pod set, but avoid soggy soil as they\'re sensitive to overwatering.</string>
    <string name="kidneybeans">KidneyBeans</string>
    <string name="pigeonpeasdesc">Pigeon peas are incredibly resilient! They thrive in well-drained soils ranging from sandy loams to heavier clays, and even tolerate some drought and salinity. They don\'t need excessive fertilizer, but a moderate amount of phosphorus (P) and potassium (K) helps them grow strong. They flourish in warm, semi-arid climates with moderate rainfall. Pigeon peas are remarkably drought-tolerant but appreciate regular watering during flowering and pod development.</string>
    <string name="pigeon_peas">Pigeon Peas</string>
    <string name="croprecomdesc">Get personalized crop recommendations based on your soil and climate conditions.</string>
    <string name="oranges">Oranges</string>
    <string name="orangedesc">Orange trees crave sunshine and well-drained, loamy soil. They dislike waterlogged roots, so avoid heavy clay. A slightly acidic to mildly alkaline pH (6.5-7.5) is ideal. Balanced NPK fertilizer is their friend, with adjustments depending on the soil. Oranges are subtropical sweethearts, loving warm weather with consistent rainfall. While watering is important, avoid extremes. They don\'t tolerate drought, but soggy roots can be deadly</string>
    <string name="pomegranate">Pomegranate</string>
    <string name="pomegranatedesc">Pomegranates thrive in well-draining soil, ideally a sandy or clay loam mix with a slightly acidic to neutral pH (6.0-7.0). They don\'t require heavy feeding, but a balanced 10-10-10 fertilizer in spring can be beneficial. These sunshine lovers flourish in hot, dry climates (zones 7-11) but can tolerate cooler regions too. Water them deeply during the first year and fruiting season, letting the soil dry slightly between soaks. Established trees are quite drought-tolerant.</string>
    <string name="apple">Apple</string>
    <string name="appledesc">Apple trees flourish in well-drained, loamy soil with a slightly acidic pH. While specific NPK ratios can vary, they generally benefit from balanced fertilizer with a slight emphasis on phosphorus (P) for fruit development. Ideally, apple trees thrive in cool climates with mild winters and distinct seasons, but some varieties can adapt to warmer regions. Watering needs depend on rainfall, but consistent moisture is crucial, especially during fruit formation.</string>
    <string name="muskmelondesc">Muskmelons thrive in well-drained, loamy soil with plenty of organic matter. For optimal growth, they need a balanced NPK fertilizer, with a slight emphasis on potassium (K) for sweetness. These warm-season crops love sunshine and temperatures between 20-32°C. They\'re fairly drought-tolerant, but consistent watering, especially during fruit development, is key for juicy melons.</string>
    <string name="muskmelon">Muskmelon</string>
    <string name="muskmelonfertreq">For beautiful, healthy melons, feed your soil before planting!  Start by applying 10-15 tonnes of aged manure, like cow dung, per acre. You can also mix in neem cake for a pest-repelling boost. When preparing the field, consider biofertilizers like Azospirillum and Phosphobacteria to enrich your soil with nitrogen-fixing microbes. Remember, muskmelons love balanced meals for their fruits, so a light side dressing of nitrogen later in the growth period is recommended. Ask your local agriculture expert for the exact amount based on your soil conditions.</string>
    <string name="mothbeansfertreq">Mothbeans are frugal and don\'t require heavy feeding! In fact, too much fertilizer can hurt. Focus on building your soil\'s natural fertility. Apply 20-25 tonnes of well-rotted Farm Yard Manure (FYM) per hectare before planting. This improves soil health, water retention, and feeds beneficial microbes that release nutrients for your mothbeans. Vermicompost is another excellent option, use 1 ton per hectare for a good boost. Remember, a healthy soil equals healthy mothbeans!</string>
    <string name="coffeefertreq">Your coffee needs a steady supply of nutrients to thrive! Organic fertilizers, like compost made from coffee pulp and leaves, can provide these. Aim to replace what your harvest removes. For every ton of coffee beans, replenish around 13 kg of nitrogen, 2.3 kg of phosphorus, and 15 kg of potassium. A soil test can help fine-tune the exact mix. Apply compost throughout the year, focusing on the root zone. Remember, healthy soil with plenty of organic matter feeds your coffee plants for long-term success.</string>
    <string name="ricefertreq">Your rice needs a healthy diet just like you! Organic fertilizers, like compost, manure, and leftover crop bits, feed the soil life which helps your rice thrive. They release nutrients slowly over time, improving soil health. Unlike chemical fertilizers, you\'ll likely need more organic matter to deliver the same amount of nutrients. Aim for 5-20 tons per hectare depending on the type of organic fertilizer. Remember, a soil test can help you determine the exact needs of your field.</string>
    <string name="chickpeafertreq">Chickpeas, being legumes, get most nitrogen (up to 75%) from Rhizobium bacteria in their roots. But for a healthy start, especially in drier soils, consider a small amount of organic nitrogen source like composted manure or neem cake before sowing. Focus on phosphorus for strong roots and good yields. Compost or bone meal are good organic options. A soil test can help determine if extra potassium or sulfur is needed, which can be added through organic sources like potash from straw or gypsum. Remember, healthy soil with plenty of organic matter is key for chickpea success!</string>
    <string name="cottonfertreq">For healthy cotton without chemicals, focus on organic fertilizers! Cotton needs a good balance of Nitrogen (N), Phosphorus (P), and Potassium (K). Aim for around 60 kg N, 30 kg P, and 15 kg K per hectare. To achieve this, use composted manure (4-5 tonnes/acre) before sowing. You can also use green manure crops like legumes, which enrich the soil with nitrogen as they decompose. Biofertilizers like Azotobacter and PSB can further boost nutrient availability. Remember, a healthy soil teeming with microbes is key for organic cotton success!</string>
</resources>